# Toby Jake Donaldson



I help businesses create truly effective ideas. I've worked with one person shops, and the world's largest businesses. From finance to food waste, recycling to religious texts and heavy industry to HIV - as well as charities, collectives and non-profits. I've led brand, campaign, behaviour change, sustainability, employee experience projects - and even taught a few courses. A problem solver at heart - overcoming challenges and achieving objectives is central in all the work I do.

# **Employment**

### Feb 2021 - Ongoing: Principal Consultant, Archetype, London, UK

Archetype (part of Next15) is a Southwark based agency working with primarily US clients - focused on creating magnetic brands.

### Feb 2021 - Nov 2021: Senior Consultant, Radley Yeldar, London, UK

Radley Yeldar is an award winning creative consultancy in the heart of London's East End. We specialise in behaviour change, brand, campaigns, strategy and sustainability - and most importantly, bringing belief to business.

Consultancy lead on: Syngenta, Shell, GSK/ViiV, BAT, Wood Group, WRAP, HS2.

#### Feb 2018 - Feb 2021: Consultant, Radley Yeldar, London, UK

Clients - Strat lead on WRAP (RN + LFHW), Wood Group, Positive Action/ViiV, Kaspersky, Syngenta, The Bible Society and others.

- Responsible for strategy, development of comms, client plans, costing, budgeting, and growth of accounts (highlight. Syngenta revenue increase from £160k to £265k pa 66% over the year).
- Working across brand, campaigns, sustainability, EX and investor engagement teams, reporting into the CSO.
- Managing in house research team / mentoring copywriting dept.

### Initiatives - On top of client work, what I bring to RY.

- Running upskilling of the consultancy, research, and creative departments (inc. sessions/inspiration pieces).
- Regular contributor to ry.com publications and other thought leadership pieces and agency marketing.
- Member of internal steering group on issues like D&I, harassment, development etc.

#### **Pitches**

Involved on the vast majority of agency pitches (led 6, won 5).

## June 2018 - Feb 2019: Strategic Planner, MRM // McCann, London, UK

MRM  $/\!\!/$  McCann is a leading full service agency with a focus on customer relationships and an integrated part of the wider McCann Worldgroup of agencies.

Clients - Retained strategist on TSB bank, Cisco and support on Vauxhall, Microsoft, Macmillan and GSK.

#### Initiatives - On top of client work..

- Directing content strategy on the in house agency insight platform 'Hot Sauce'.
- Selected as one of ten McCann Worldgroup staff to travel to Costa Rica to produce and deliver a course on strategy and behaviour change for Raleigh International - including a presentation to the British Ambassador. I still work with Raleigh, independently on other projects.

### Pitches

• Involved in several pitches - wins for Microsoft AI and Macmillan.

# May 2017 - May 2018: Junior Planner, MRM // McCann, London, UK

Clients - Retained strategist on TSB bank and Pernod Ricard and support on Vauxhall and GSK. Reporting into the Head of Planning.

# January 2017 - April 2017: Junior Strategist (Contract), ZAK, London, UK

ZAK is an independent creative agency with a singular focus: generating big brand ideas that engage under 30s.

**Clients** - Day to day strategy running briefings, internal workshops and research.

• **New Balance** - worked with the CSO on strategy for both existing campaigns and new business, including the award winning 'Blackout Squad' campaign.

#### **Initiatives**

 Responsible for the set up and running of the Global Insight Network (GIN), writing and researching monthly trend reports, sourcing and managing contributors. The network reports gained over 1000 paying subscribers, including Facebook and Google.

### August 2016 - November 2016: Online Marketing (Contract), Lamudi. Berlin, Germany

Lamudi is an online real estate marketplace operating in 34 countries.

• Set up and ran online marketing operations for the Mexican, Peruvian, Philippine and Pakistani markets. The Mexican and Philippine markets are now the 1st and 3rd largest for Lamudi globally. Responsible for using data, insight, research and social listening to develop digital creative over a wide range of media channels globally, while liaising with local teams and clients worldwide.

### July 2015 - July 2016: Field Specialist, Apple. Global (NDA Bound)

Part of a team of 10 based out of London, working on location worldwide over 11 countries and in 12 languages. Project bound by indefinite NDA.

- Planning, troubleshooting and problem solving working with teams in the UK, US & Japan ensuring the smooth progress of the project to completion.
- Working covertly worldwide, planning and carrying out assignments using unreleased Apple hardware and software. Field and 'lockdown' office work included in this.

Previous; KRM-PER, Compass Group, Scandlines Sverige, the Club Company, G4S, Merchant's Bar, Brindley & Co Solicitors.

## **Education**



## Sept. 2013 - Oct. 2015: Marketing MSc (Academic Scholarship) - Instituto Universitário de Lisboa (Lisbon, Portugal)

Master of Science in Marketing.

- Key courses: Branding, Consumer Behaviour, Strategic Brand Management, Relationship Marketing & Communications.
- Thesis: 'Brand Love & the Ideal Self: An Investigation into Anthropomorphic Function in Brand Love' (published and available on Amazon).
- Al Portuguese Language.



### May 2015 - Oct. 2015: Sustainability MSc - Lunds Universitet (Lund, Sweden)

6 month exchange.

- Key courses: CSR, Innovation Management, Sustainability, Scandinavian Models of Equality.
- Al Swedish Language.



### Sept. 2010- June 2013- Psychology BSc - University of Leeds (Leeds, UK) (2.1)

Bachelor of Science in Psychology.

- Key courses: Advanced Social Psychology, Memory & Language, Cognitive Neuroscience, Personality & Intelligence, and Psychology in the Media.
- Dissertation 'Conceptual Combinations; Forming Impressions of Brand Extensions'.

# **Training/Certifications**

- Facebook, Google, APA, IPG McCann, Effectiveness BPS and various strategy/creative courses.
- CISL Business Sustainability Management course (University of Cambridge 2021)
- Other; Tier 1 Medic RLSS.